Tejas Salunkhe O Featured

Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming having experience of working on software development technologies (Core Java, J2EE, JDBC, Servlet, JSP, Hibernate, Maven, Spring MVC, PostGres, Tomcat, JBoss, Webservices- REST, SOAP)



Current Designation: Engineer - Java Developer Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 10 Month(s)

Current Company: Larsen & Toubro Infotech Limited Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Mumbai Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Computers]

Pref. Location: Mumbai, Mumbai Suburbs, Navi Mumbai
Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Core Java, J2EE, JDBC, Servlet, JSP, Hibernate, Maven, Spring

MVC,MySQL,PostGres,SQL,ClearCase,Jenkins,GIT, Web Services, Rest, SOAP, JAX-WS, Multithreading, OOPS, Design

Patterns, Software Development, Jboss Application Server, Tomcat, Requirement Analysis

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

Software enthusiast looking for development opportunities, also a post graduate in advance computing from CDAC-Mumbai. Result-oriented Professional with 2.10 years of experience in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Core Java, J2EE, JDBC, Servlet, JSP, Hibernate, Maven, Spring MVC, MySQL, PostGres, SQL, Tomcat, JBoss, Clear Case, Jenkins, GIT, REST, SOAP Webservices

Work Experience

Larsen & Toubro Infotech Limited as Engineer - Java Developer Mar 2019 to Till Date

Java developer, working on all the phases of SDLC. Design and implementation of application components. Requirement gathering and analysis, responsible for creating SRS, HLR and designing of application components. Detecting and resolving bugs, enhancing and developing new features in product.

Rolta Bl BigData Analytics Pvt. Ltd as Software Engineer (Product Development) Mar 2018 to Mar 2019

Design and implementation of the application components.

Research and development of product related technologies.

Working on phases of SDLC such as requirement gathering and analysis, Desiging, Coding, Testing, Application Implementation, Deployment and maintainance.

 $Technogies\ Used(Java(J2SE,J2EE),\ SpringMVC,\ Hibernate,\ Maven,\ SQL,PostGres,\ InfluxDB,\ RestFul,$

Soap, Tomcat, JBoss Wildfly, Tools-Clearcase, Jeankins)

Education

PG: PG Diploma (Computers) from Centre for Development of Advanced Computing (CDAC)-mumbai in 2018

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Post Graduate Diploma in Advance Computing (PG-DAC)

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
JAVA	7 and 8	2020	2 Year(s) 9 Month(s)
JBOSS Application Server	10x	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
POSTGRES		2020	2 Year(s) 9 Month(s)
SPRING MVC		2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
REST(JAX-WS) and SOAP Webservices		2020	2 Year(s) 9 Month(s)
J2EE		2020	2 Year(s) 9 Month(s)
MAVEN		2020	2 Year(s) 9 Month(s)
Hibernate		2020	2 Year(s) 9 Month(s)
JSP Servlets		2020	2 Year(s) 9 Month(s)
GIT		2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			
Marathi	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: 4-Flight Client: Thales

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Apr 2019 - Till Date Role: Programmer Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 11

Skill Used: J2Se, J2Ee, Servlet, JSP, Hibernate, Maven, Postgres, Restful, Soap, WSDL, JavaSE, JavaSE, Web Services, JBoss, Tomcat, MySQL, Postgresql, Clearcase, Github

Role Description: Java developer, working on all the phases of SDLC. Design and implementation of application components. Requirement gathering and analysis, responsible for SRS, HLR and designing of application components. Detecting and resolving bugs

Project Details: This is a B2B application developed for aerospace flight controllers who operate international, domestic and event based flights. This business intelligent application allows flight controllers to make accurate and on-time decisions of flight management. Data from radars which are monitoring flights on the operational unit is brought into application and accordingly the flight movements are displayed to controller, using which the flight controllers make decisions to guide the flight and improve overall operational effectiveness which helps in avoiding accidents as well as helps in improving business.

Project Title: OT Extractor

Client: Cairn

Nature of Employment: Full Time **Duration: Mar 2018 - Mar 2019** Role: Programmer Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 8

Skill Used: Technical Skills-JavaSE, JavaEE, Servlet, JSP, Hibernate, Maven, Postgres, Restful, Soap, Web Services, JBoss, Tomcat, MySQL, Postgresql, Clearcase, Github

Role Description: IOT-Fusion

Working on phases of SDLC such as Requirement gathering and Analysis, Desiging, Coding, Testing, Application implementation, Deployment and Maintenance. Research and Development of a new product (OT Extractor) using InfluxDB as a Database.

Project Details: A web based Business Intelligence application that allows personnel to make accurate and on time decisions at all level of the organisation. Data from sensors on the operational unit is brought into this application to improve the performance and overall operational effectiveness of the organisation by aligning the work-process efforts of the personnel with the goals of the business

Project Title: Oneview Client: RaasGas Qatar

Duration: Mar 2018 - Mar 2019 Nature of Employment: Full Time

Role: Programmer Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: J2Se, J2Ee, Servlet, JSP, Hibernate, Maven, Postgres, Restful, Soap, WSDL, JavaSE, JavaEE, Web Services,

JBoss, Tomcat, MySQL, Postgresql, Clearcase, Github

Project Details: A web based Business Intelligence application that allows personnel to make accurate and on time decisions at all level of the organisation. Data from sensors on the operational unit is brought into this application to improve the performance and overall operational effectiveness of the organisation by aligning the work-process efforts of the personnel with the goals of the business

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time